Yahoo!
!مرحى
Eh? You're not going to ski, Dad?
ماذا؟ لن تتزلّج يا أبي؟
Don't be stupid!
حمقاء
I'm taking in this nice, cloudless sky first...
أنا آخذ وقتي في الاستمتاع بمنظر هذه السماء الصافية أوّلاً
Along with the grandeur of this snowy white landscape!
كما هذا الكساء الثلجي الباهر ناصع البياض
Damn. I knew I shouldn't have come...
تبّاً، كنتُ أعرف أنّه لم يجدر بي القدوم
Eh?! You lost the key to the rental cabin?!
ماذا؟ فقدت مفتاح المقصورة المستأجرة؟
Geez! It's all thanks to you two!
يا إلهي، هذا بسبب ما فعلتماه
Guess all we can do is call the manager to bring a duplicate key.
بأيّ حال، كلّ ما يمكننا فعله هو الاتّصال بالمشرف وطلب مفتاح بديل
There aren't any phone booths around here,
لا توجد حُجر هواتف في هذه المنطقة
that cabin is still under construction,
والمقصورة مقابلنا لا تزال قيد البناء
and the ski bus already left...
وحافلة التزلج غادرت بالفعل
The only thing nearby is that one lodge up there...
ما بقربنا هو ذاك المنزل فحسب
Me, ask help from some upstart with a lodge there? Forget it!
!أطلب مساعدة وغد ثريّ يبني منزلاً هنا؟ مستحيل
No choice! We'll open it by force!
!لا خيار آخر، سنفتحه بالقوّة
No, don't!
!لا تفعل يا عمّ
Stop, Dad!
!كلا يا أبي
Say! Are you...
...ماذا؟ أيمكن أنّك
Oh! It is Mori Kogoro-san, the detective!
إنّه أنت بالفعل، المتحرّي موري كوغورو-سان
I always read about your brilliant work in the newspaper!
!أقرأ دائماً عن تحريّاتك المذهلة في الصحف
Wow, what a magnificent lodge!
!يا للمنزل الجميل
Such an elegant color and design!
!تصميمٌ ولون خشبيّ يخطف الأنظار
Who was talking about rich upstarts just a minute ago?
ألم تكن من ينعت الوغد الثريّ قبل قليل؟
Come to think of it, I haven't heard your names yet.
بالمناسبة، لم أتعرف على اسمك بعد
Are you Mori-san's daughter?
أأنتِ ابنة موري-سان؟
Yes! I'm Ran!
أجل، أُدعى ران
This is Edogawa Conan-kun. We're watching him for a friend of ours.
هذا إيدوغاوا كونان-كن، ابن أحد الأصدقاء نعتني به
This lion-shaped door decoration is superb, too!
!تصميم الأسد على الباب رائع أيضاً
I was hoping for a horse,
أردتُ حصاناً
but I guess that was asking too much...
لكن ربما طلبتُ الكثير
A horse?
حصان؟
T-That's true. Horses would be better than lions...
صـ-صحيح، الحصان أفضل من الأسد
No, no, that's not what I mean...
...كلا، لم أقصد ذلك
Dr. Oyama!
!دكتور أوياما
Oh! Nakahara-kun!
ناكاهارا-كن؟
What took you so long?!
(ناكاهارا كاوري (30 باحثة في كليّة الطب لجامعة توتو، قسم الجراحة
Everyone's been waiting!
كان الجميع بانتظارك
Who are these folks?
من الأشخاص رفقتك؟
Oh? You're all doctors at the same university?
ماذا؟ أنتم أطّباء في نفس الجامعة إذاً
Yep! We're all assistants for Dr. Oyama!
أجل، جميعنا مساعدون للدكتور أوياما
Doctors are very factional, you see.
فالأطبّاء يميلون للتجمّع تحت راية
I've been studying under the doctor for dozens of years now.
أنا أدرس تحت جناح الدكتور منذ عشرات الأعوام
I transferred here three years ago from some future-less professor.
انتقلتُ هنا قبل 3 أعوام من بروفسور أضعف مستقبلاً
I'm really glad to be where I am now.
أشعر بالسرور لكوني حيث أنا الآن
The essay he presented the other day was wonderful!
البحث الذي نشره قبل بضعة أيّام كان مذهلاً
Oh, "Gene Therapy as Treatment for Cancer of the Large Intestine"?
تقصدين "المداواة الجينية كعلاج لسرطان الأمعاء الغليظة"، صحيح؟
The whole medical school is praising his essay right now!
كليّة الطب بأسرها تُطري على بحثه الآن
Come now, with my brains, it was a piece of cake!
كان أمراً يسيراً بعقلي
Thank you for the meal!
شكراً على الطعام
Oh no! I forgot to buy snacks to go with our drinks!
كلا! نسيتُ شراء أكلات خفيفة مع الساكي
I'll go pick some up at the shop at the bottom of the mountain.
سأذهب لشراء بعضها من المتجر أسفل الجبل
Could you get some chips?
هلّا جلبتِ رقائق بطاطا؟
Dried cuttlefish for me!
!حبّار مجفف لي
I'll have a salad!
!أنا أريد سلطة
Yes, yes. Here, write it all down so I know what to buy.
حسناً، حسناً، اكتبوا كيلا أنسى طلباتكم
Yes, ma'am.
حاضر
The convenience store closes before 10:00, so hurry!
!يغلق متجر البقّالة ذاك قبل العاشرة لذا أسرعي
Yeah, I know.
أجل، أعرف
Hey! What time is it?!
ما الوقت الآن؟
8:58...
...الثامنة وثمان وخمسون
Uh oh!
!كلا
What's going on?
ما الخطب؟
A TV show.
مسلسل تلفازي
He's addicted to a melodrama that gets 30% ratings!
إنّه مدمن على ميلودراما نسبة مشاهداتها 30% الآن
Oh, I watch that show, too!
!أشاهدها أيضاً
Huh? Where are you off to, Dr. Tobita?
ماذا؟ أين تذهب يا دكتور توبيتا؟
Night skiing. I haven't gotten my fix yet.
تزلّج ليلي
I should be back by around 11:00.
سأعود قبل الحادية عشرة
Well, I guess I'll take a nice,
سآخذ حماماً دافئاً باسترخاء
relaxing bath until the snacks arrive.
حتى وصول الأكلات الخفيفة إذاً
Say, did you call the cabin manager about our key?
هل اتّصلتِ بمشرف المقصورة بشأن مفتاحنا؟
I completely forgot!
!نسيتُ تماماً
That's all right! You can stay the night here!
!لا بأس، يمكنكم المبيت هنا
Your father can't exactly leave in his state...
فلا تستطيعون العودة بحال أبيك
I'm going to throw out the trash.
سأرمي القمامة
Okay!
حسناً
Wait! Tsutomu-san! Don't leave me!
!انتظر يا تسوتومو-سان !لا تذهب لأيّ مكان
I have to, Mitsue-san. We can never be together.
عليّ ذلك يا ميتسوي-سان، فلا نستطيع البقاء سويّاً أبداً
So, please! Forget about me!
!لذا أرجوك، انسي أمري
Why?! Why can't we be together?!
!لمَ؟ لمَ لا نستطيع البقاء سويّاً؟
I'm back!
!رجعت
Welcome back, Kaori!
مرحباً بعودتك يا كاوري
It must've been rough with the sudden blizzard!
لا بدّ أنّك عانيتِ مع العاصفة المفاجئة
Dr. Tobita!
!دكتور توبيتا
Man, can't possibly night ski with that blizzard out there!
!يا إلهي، كيف لي أن أتزلّج بتلك العاصفة
That warms me up!
!يُدفئني
Oh, are we drinking?
أتشربون؟
How was your bath?
كيف كان حمّامك؟
Just wonderful!
!رائعاً
Oh? I had asked for a salad...
...ماذا؟ طلبتُ سلطة
Sorry, they were sold out.
آسفة، نفدتْ
And there was no ice cream.
كما لم تكن هناك مثلجات
Who asked for ice cream in this weather?
من طلب مثلجات في هذا الطقس البارد؟
Maybe it was Dr. Oyama? He does love ice cream...
ربما كان الدكتور أوياما، فهو يحبّ المثلجات
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
His TV drama ended at 10:00, so where could he be?
،يُفترض أنّ تلك الدراما تنتهي عند العاشرة ألا ترون أنّه تأخّر؟
Dr. Oyama always tapes the show
يسجلها الدكتور أوياما دوماً
and replays the best scenes afterward.
ويعيد أفضل المشاهد لاحقاً
Damn you... This was your original intent all along...
،تبّاً لك... كانت هذه نيّتك من البداية ...قتلي في المنزل الجبلي
But you won't get away with this!
!لكن لن تفلت
The great detective, Mori Kogoro, is here!
!فالمتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو هنا
I'm sure that he, if anyone, will get this message!
!سيلاحظ هذه الرسالة بلا شكّ
Eh? Mori Kogoro?
ماذا؟ موري كوغورو؟
The guy always in the newspaper?
الشخص المذكور دوماً في الصّحف؟
Yes! My dad's a detective!
أجل، أبي مُتحرٍّ
It's past 11:00 now.
تجاوزت الحادية عشرة
I think he's taking a bit too long...
أراه تأخّر كثيراً
I'll go see what's up.
سأذهب لتفقّد أمره
Huh? He's that famous detective?
ماذا؟ إنّه ذاك المتحرّي الشهير؟
Looks sure can be deceiving...
المظاهر خدّاعة بالفعل
K-Kaori!
!كاوري
Hey! What happened?!
!ماذا حصل؟
Dr. Oyama!
!دكتور أوياما
It's too late. He's dead.
فات الأوان، فارق الحياة
This can't be!
!لا يمكن
For now, let's untie his ropes...
لنفك رباط جثّته بأيّ حال
Stop right there!
!لا تلمسوه أكثر
I'd appreciate it if you don't mess up the murder scene!
لا تخرّبوا مسرح جريمة قتل
Dad! They can't get police cars
أبي! لا يمكن للشرطة أو الإسعاف
or an ambulance here in this blizzard!
!القدوم هنا مع العاصفة
That so? Then I have no choice.
هكذا إذاً، لا خيار لديّ
Looks like I, the great Mori Kogoro, will have to take charge here!
يبدو أنّ على المتحرّي... العظيم موري كوغورو !تولّي المسؤولية هنا
You're still so drunk!
لا تزال ثملاً
I'll ask just to be safe--
سأسأل من باب الحيطة
no one's touched anything in the room, right?
لم يلمس أحد شيئاً في غرفته، صحيح؟
No, nothing aside from Dr. Oyama's body.
أجل، لا شيء غير جثّة الطبيب أوياما
You found him first, Nakahara-san.
أفترض أنّ الأمر ينطبق عليك أيضاً يا مكتشفة الجثّة، ناكاهارا-سان
That's right. I saw him covered in blood
أجل، رأيته غارقاً في الدماء
and fell down in the doorway.
وسقطتُ عند الباب
Was there anything of value in this room?
أكان هناك شيءٌ ذو قيمة في هذه الغرفة؟
He does have a safe in the cabinet to the right of the TV.
يملك خزنةً في الحجرة بجوار التلفاز
Here?
هنا؟
It's all scratched up!
إنّها مخدوشة
Do you know what's inside this safe?
أتعرفون ما داخل هذه الخزنة؟
Cash, I assume.
مالٌ على الأغلب
He always carried large sums of money with him.
فقد كان يحمل مالاً كثيراً باستمرار معه
So I guess they were after money...
كانت جريمةً هدفها المال إذاً
What's with this blood trail?
ما خطب أثر الدم هذا؟
It's almost as if he crawled to the wall...
كأنّه زحف للحائط
And why is he sitting formally?
ولمَ يجلس برسمية؟
The blood on the table stops cleanly...
الدم على الطاولة متوقف عند خطّ بوضوح
Ah. The tablecloth slipped off...
هكذا إذاً، سقط غطاء الطاولة
Marks from the bloodied rope!
علامات من الحبال الدامية؟
Could this be a dying message from Dr. Oyama?!
أيمكن أنّها رسالة احتضار من أوياما-سان؟
So they used tape on the window to muffle the sound, then snuck in...
استعمل لاصقاً على النافذة لكتم الصوت إذاً ثم تسلل
They were even nice enough to leave footprints outside the window!
كان لطيفاً بما يكفي لترك آثار أقدام خارج النافذة أيضاً
I think I've got this figured out!
أظنني فهمت الصورة العامة
No "hmmms"! Get outta here!
!بلا همهمة! اخرج
I hate to ask, but could you examine him for me?
اعذروني، لكن هلّا فحصتموه؟
As doctors, you're more qualified than I am.
فأنتم الأطبّاء مؤهلون أكثر منّي
Right.
حسناً
Man, this is bad!
فظيع
Even his beloved gold watch is covered in blood!
حتّى ساعته الذهبية العزيزة عليه مغطاة بالدماء
Quit joking around at a time like this!
اترك التفاهات جانباً في وقت كهذا
I estimate his time of death to be between 9:30 and 10:00 pm.
وقت الوفاة المقدّر هو بين التاسعة والنصف والعاشرة
I see. So it was during his TV drama?
فهمت، أثناء مشاهدته للدراما التلفزية إذاً؟
Yes.
أجل
There are countless cuts all over his body,
توجد ندوب قطع على سائر جسده
but it appears he died of suffocation
لكن يبدو أنّه مات اختناقاً
after having both lungs punctured.
بعد تعرّض كلتا رئتيه للثقب
Suffocation?
اختناق؟
Basically, with holes in his lungs,
بوجود ثقوب في رئتيه
he couldn't hold air to breathe.
لا يمكنه الاحتفاظ بالهواء للتنفّس بشكل رئيسي
He probably suffered terribly for ten or fifteen minutes...
عانى كثيراً من عشر إلى خمس عشرة دقيقة غالباً
That's horrible!
!فظيع
Who on earth would do this?!
!من قد يُقدم على فعلة كهذه؟
This was most likely done for monetary gain.
كانت جريمةً هدفها المال على الأرجح
After breaking in through the window,
،بعد تسلّله عبر النافذة
the killer attacked and tied up Dr. Oyama, who was watching TV,
هاجم القاتل أوياما-سان الذي كان يشاهد التلفاز وقام بتقييده
then demanded the safe combination, but didn't get it.
ثمّ طلب منه توليفة الخزانة، لكنّه رفض البوح
Enraged, the culprit stabbed Oyama-san and fled back out the window.
فطعن القاتلُ أوياما-سان غضباً ثمّ هرب من النافذة
Ugh, talk about dense...
...لا أمل منه
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Say, he was tied up, right?
كان الرجل مقيّداً، صحيح؟
Then he was super lucky the killer didn't take his gold watch!
فهو محظوظ إذاً لأنّ القاتل لم يأخذ ساعته الذهبية
How odd for someone after money to overlook a watch like that...
هذا غريب، كيف يتغاضى مجرم هدفه المال عن ساعة كهذه؟
Then that means...
...هذا يعني
...that the killer must be pretty stupid!
!أنّ القاتل غبيّ جداً
But don't you think the killer must've been gutsy?
لكن ألا تظنون أنّ القاتل جريء؟
See? Look at the footprints outside!
!انظروا لآثار الأقدام خارج النافذة
They come straight to this room!
أتى لهذه الغرفة مباشرةً
So what?
وما في ذلك؟
If it was me, I'd be afraid someone else was in the room
لو كنتُ مكانه، لخشيت تواجد شخص آخر في الغرفة
and would sneak around and peek in before going inside!
فتفقدت في الأرجاء واسترقت النظر قبل الدخول
Dad! Does that mean...
...أبي، أيعني هذا
Scratching the safe and tying Oyama-san up was camouflage,
خدش الخزنة وتقييد أوياما-سان كان تضليلاً
meant to make it look like this was about money...
كي نعتقد أنّها جريمة للمال
The killer knew Oyama-san would be watching TV alone then...
كان القاتل يعرف أنّ أوياما-سان سيكون أمام التلفاز بمفرده آنذاك
In other words, one of you four is the killer!
!ما يعني أنّ القاتل أحدكم الأربعة
What?!
!مستحيل
What the hell?!
!ماذا؟
Then let's hear each of your alibis between 9:30 and 10:00.
لنسمع حجج غيابكم من بين التاسعة والنصف للعاشرة إذاً
I was at the convenience store.
كنتُ في المتجر
I left at 9:00 and returned at around 9:50.
غادرتُ عند التاسعة ورجعت عند التاسعة والخمسين
The only snacks that were sold out were salad and ice cream.
من بين الأكلات التي طلبها مني الجميع كانت السلطة والمثلجات وحدهما ما نفدا
But you could've finished sooner if you rushed in your car.
لكن كان بإمكانك الانتهاء أبكر إذا أسرعتِ بالقيادة
It takes over forty minutes round-trip!
!تحتاج الرحلة الكاملة ما يفوق 40 دقيقة
If you think I'm lying, you can try it with my car!
!إذا ظننتني أكذب فجرّب بسيارتي
I went night skiing, a ski slope also forty minutes round-trip.
كنتُ خارجاً لتزلّج ليلي، وتستغرق مسافة منحدر التزلّج 40 دقيقة أيضاً
Do you have proof of this?
ألديك دليل لذلك؟
Sure do.
أجل
This lift ticket has today's date.
تذكرة المصعد تحمل تاريخ اليوم
See, it even has the time.
انظر، بها الوقت حتّى
I cleaned up and washed things with Ran-chan and Conan-kun.
قمتُ بالتنظيف والغسيل رفقة ران-تشان وكونان-كن
That's true, Dad.
إنّها الحقيقة يا أبي
She only left for two or three minutes to throw out the trash.
غادرت بين دقيقتين لثلاث فقط لإخراج القمامة
I was taking a bath from 9:30 until shortly after 10:00.
كنتُ أستحم من التاسعة والنصف حتّى بُعَيد العاشرة
There's one other person besides Kanazawa-san with a flimsy alibi.
يوجد شخص آخر مع كانازاوا-سان بحجّة غياب ضعيفة
B-Blood stains?!
!بـ-بقع دماء؟
Huh? But why isn't there any blood on the sofa?
ماذا؟ لكن لمَ لا يوجد أيّ منها على الأريكة؟
Did someone put it here after the blood dried?!
أوضعها أحد هنا بعد جفاف الدم؟
Wait a minute. The blood-smeared tablecloth... Could it be?!
لحظة، غطاء الطاولة المليء بالدماء... أيمكن؟
It matches perfectly! This lighter was sitting here!
مُتطابق، كانت هذه القدّاحة هنا
Could this be...
...أيمكن أنّ هذه
Come to think of it, this afternoon, Oyama-san said...
...صحيح، قال أوياما-سان ظهيرة اليوم
I was hoping for a horse, but I guess that was asking too much...
أردتُ حصاناً، لكن ربما طلبتُ الكثير
That was when he asked me and Ran our names...
كان ذلك عندما سألني وران عن اسمينا
That's it! A horse! That's what he meant!
!فهمت! حصان! كان هذا ما قصده
This really is Oyama-san's dying message!
!هذه رسالة احتضار لأوياما-سان بالفعل
It explains his formal way of sitting,
يفسّر ذلك طريقة جلوسه
and the bloody lighter on the sofa!
!والقدّاحة الدامية على الأريكة
And just as his dying message says,
...وكما تقول رسالة احتضاره
the killer was that person!
!القاتل هو ذاك الشخص
Hey, mister. There's something weird on the sofa--
انظر يا عمّ، يوجد شيء غريب على الأريكة
Knock it off, you damn kid!
!يكفي أيّها الشقيّ
What's wrong, Dad?!
ما الخطب يا أبي؟
I think he's drunk.
أظن أنّه ثمل
Don't be stupid! I ain't drunk!
!أحمق! لست ثملاً
I figured it all out!
اكتشفتُ الأمر
Eh?! What, now?! What did you figure out?!
ماذا؟ ما الذي اكتشفته؟
The killer. I just now figured out who stabbed Oyama-san!
القاتل، اكتشفتُ هويّة القاتل !الذي طعن أوياما-سان
First is Tobita-san, who went night skiing.
نبدأ بتوبيتا-سان الذي ذهب لتزلّج ليلي
He wouldn't have made up a fake story that could be easily verified.
لن يختلق قصّة كاذبة يمكن التحقق منها بسهولة
Next is you, Ezumi-san.
التالية إيزومي-سان
You only left Ran and Conan for two or three minutes.
تركتِ ران وكونان بين دقيقتين لثلاث فقط
Not enough time to have killed Oyama-san.
ليس وقتاً كافياً لقتل أوياما-سان
Which only leaves Kanazawa-san and Nakahara-san without alibis.
يترك هذا كانازاوا-سان وناكاهارا-سان الاثنين بلا حجّة غياب
Hold on! I bought the snacks that everyone asked--
...انتظر! اشتريتُ الأكلات كما طلب الجميع
Then how much did it all cost?
كم كلّفت إذاً؟
I forget!
!نسيت
No, you didn't forget. You don't know.
كلا، لم تنسي. بل لم تعرفي
Because you bought large amounts of all kinds of snacks in advance.
لأنّك اشتريتِ كمية كبيرة من مختلف الأكلات سلفاً
You bought them this afternoon when you bought the food for dinner.
اشتريتِها ظهيرة اليوم عندما ابتعتِ مكوّنات العشاء
Before the murder, you took everyone's orders,
قبل الجريمة، أخذتِ طلبات الجميع
and then pretended to leave in your car.
وتظاهرتِ بالمغادرة في سيّارتك
You then stopped somewhere
توقّفتِ في مكان بعدها
and pulled out the snacks they ordered.
وأخرجتِ الأكلات التي طلبوها
Now that you had an alibi, you went and murdered Oyama-san.
أصبحت لديك حجّة غياب الآن، فقتلتِ أوياما-سان
Don't be stupid; you have no proof!
لا تكن أحمق، لا دليل لديك
No, you know yourself that there's proof
كلا، أنت تعرفين أنه يوجد دليل
in this room that you did it.
في هذه الغرفة يثبت أنّك القاتلة
Have a look at the table.
انظروا للطاولة
The blood ends cleanly.
يتوقف أثر الدماء بوضوح
Doesn't it seem like something was on it?
ألا يبدو كما لو كان هناك شيء عليها؟
The tablecloth!
!غطاء الطاولة
Please put it on the table so that it matches with the blood stains.
ضعوه على الطاولة بحيث يطابق بقع الدم رجاءً
That is Oyama-san's dying message.
إنّها رسالة احتضار أوياما-سان
How is this a message?
كيف لهذه أن تكون رسالة؟
Think back. Oyama-san died while sitting formally.
تذكّروا، مات أوياما-سان وهو جالس برسميّة
It should start to become clear.
يُفترض أن يتّضح لكم
Each of your names includes characters used in shogi (Japanese chess).
فبأسمائكم رموز تُستعمل في الشوغي
S-Shogi?
الشوغي؟
Say, Dr. Oyama always said how a horse would make the full set.
كان الدكتور أوياما يقول دائماً أن حصاناً سيكمل المجموعة
Yes. You make up all the pieces but a knight.
أجل، تشكّلون القطع كاملةً باستثناء الفارس
Ran. Take the lighter on the sofa and put it on the tablecloth.
ران، خذي القدّاحة على الأريكة وضعيها على غطاء الطاولة
Right.
حاضر
There's only one place the blood on the lighter matches the tablecloth.
يوجد موضع واحد يطابق فيه الدم على القدّاحة الأثر بغطاء الطاولة
Here.
هنا
Kaori
كاوري
This is a lance!
!هذا رمح
Yes. That is a lance's starting position.
صحيح، إنّه موضع بداية الرمح
This is a dying message that gives your name, Nakahara Kaori-san!
أي أنّها رسالة احتضار !تكشف اسمك يا ناكاهارا كاوري-سان
But how did you know that before putting the tablecloth on the table?
لكن كيف عرفت ذلك قبل وضع غطاء الطاولة عليها؟
Look closely.
أمعنوا النظر
That square is the only one with long blood trails.
ذاك المربّع هو الوحيد بأثر دم طويل
In other words, it was on the very edge of the table.
أي أنّه كان على حافة الطاولة
I see!
فهمت
It just coincidentally turned out that way!
!حصل هذا بمحض المصادفة
Then why did you move it?
لمَ حرّكتِه إذاً؟
It was you who tossed the tablecloth aside, yes?
ألم تكوني من خلع غطاء الطاولة؟
No! It must've happened when the killer and Dr. Oyama struggled!
كلا! حصل ذلك عندما صارع !الدكتور أوياما القاتل حتماً
No. The blood on the table ends cleanly,
كلا، الدم على الطاولة متوقف بوضوح
and the sofa the bloody lighter was on has no blood at all.
ولم يكن هناك أيّ دم على الأريكة التي كانت القدّاحة عليها
This is proof that someone moved it after the blood dried.
هذا دليل على تحريك أحد لها بعد جفاف الدم
In other words, the killer must've returned to the scene,
أي أنّ القاتل عاد لمسرح الجريمة
noticed the message, and tossed it aside!
ولاحظ الرسالة وأزاحها
Am I wrong, Nakahara Kaori-san?!
أأنا مخطئ يا ناكاهارا كاوري-سان؟
Kaori...
...كاوري
Your undoing was that you noticed the message after you screamed.
كان هلاكك في ملاحظتك الرسالة بعد صراخك
And one other thing--
...وشيء آخر
you said they were out of salad and ice cream,
قلتِ أنّ السلطة والمثلجات نفدت
but setting aside the salad, selling out of ice cream is--
...لكن بتجاهل السلطة، يستحيل أن تنفد المثلـ
That's enough!
!يكفي
That's right! I killed him!
!صحيح، قتلتُه
Why would you do that to him, Kaori?!
لم أقدمتِ على هذا يا كاوري؟
You got along so well!
!كنتما على وفاق
Yes, he was like a father to me.
أجل، كان كالأب لي
That's why I couldn't forgive him...
لذا لم أستطع مسامحته
I couldn't believe he'd steal my paper from me!
!لم أستطع تصديق سرقته بحثي
Paper? You don't mean...
...بحثك؟ أتقصدين
"Gene Therapy as Treatment for Cancer of the Large Intestine"?!
المداواة الجينية كعلاج لسرطان" الأمعاء الغليظة" التي نشرها الدكتور؟
That's right! He stole it from me!
!صحيح! سرقه مني
After I had spent six whole years pouring my life into that essay!
بعدما قضيتُ 6 أعوام في كتابة !ذاك البحث بكلّ روحي
Yes, the paper I wrote for my late father's sake...
...أجل، البحث الذي كتبته لأبي الراحل
My father died of large intestinal cancer when I was very young.
مات أبي في صغري من سرطان الأمعاء الغليظة
The reason I became a doctor devoted to large intestinal cancer
أصبحتُ طبيبة متخصصة في سرطان الأمعاء الغليظة
was to prevent any more cases like my father's!
كيلا يكون هناك المزيد من الضحايا مثل أبي
Yet, after he stole the paper I had finally completed, that man...
مع ذلك، سرق ذاك الرجل ...البحث مني بعدما أتممته أخيراً
There's no point.
لا جدوى
Nobody'll listen to you if you said you wrote it.
لن يصغي أحد إن قلتِ أنّها من تأليفك
But society will pay attention if a famous professor makes it public!
لكن سينتبه المجتمع إذا نشرها بروفسور شهير
I'm sure your father would be happier that way!
سيكون والدك الراحل أسعد بهذا حتماً
It was then that I devised this plan.
فكّرتُ بهذه الخطة آنذاك
I decided to kill the man who stomped on my feelings for my father
قرّرتُ قتل الرجل الذي داس على مشاعري تجاه أبي
by puncturing his lungs, one of the worst ways to die...
بإحدى أشدّ الطرق ألماً، الموت بثقب الرئتين
But I never once imagined he would leave a dying message
لكن لم يخطر لي أن يترك رسالة احتضار
during those ten to fifteen minutes of agony!
في ربع ساعة المعاناة تلك
But great detective.
لكن أيّها المتحرّي العظيم
There was one mistake in your theory.
كان هناك خطأ في نظريّتك
I had predicted the ice cream and salad.
تكهّنتُ بالسلطة والمثلجات
They were sold out of salad, but I did buy ice cream.
نفدت السلطة، لكنّي اشتريت المثلجات
Then why?
لمَ إذاً؟
It melted inside the car.
ذابت داخل السيّارة
I had everyone's snacks ready,
جهّزتُ أكلات الجميع
and told myself, "OK, time to kill him."
"وأخبرتُ نفسي "حسناً، حان وقت قتله
And then I suddenly thought back to my father.
ثم عادت إليّ ذكريات أبي فجأةً
After spacing out for a while, the car's heater had melted it...
وبعد شرود ذهني لبرهة، أذابت مدفأة السيّارة المثلجات
To think his ice cream would trip me up...
...لم أتصوّر أن توقع بي مثلجات ذاك الرجل
It's ridiculous!
!يا للحماقة
Dying messages. Sometimes, they're expressed in unusual ways.
رسائل الاحتضار، يُعبّر عنها أحياناً بطرق غير مألوفة
Got your angel!
!أطحت بملاكك
Your silver general is going to waste!
!أهدرت قائدك الفضيّ
Alright! Now it's finished!
!رائع! انتهيت الآن
Sometimes, when you change your perspective of something ordinary...
...عندما تغيّر منظورك عن شيء عاديّ أحياناً
Look from above!
انظر من الأعلى
Idiot
أحمق
Idiot?!
أحمق؟
Why, you!
!أنت
Dead in the pool?!
مات في المسبح؟
He drowned to death.
مات غرقاً
Just because you've been in water before
مجرد دخولك الماء سابقاً
doesn't make you an expert!
!لا يجعلك خبيراً
Don't tell me you painted what you saw from here?!
أرسمت هذه بناءً على ما رأيته من هنا؟
This is! Ah, now I get it! That person was the killer!
!هذه... فهمت الآن! القاتل هو ذاك الشخص
Yes, this was a murder made to look like an accident!
صحيح، كانت جريمة قتل زُيّفت لتبدو حادثة
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة كونان
"The Sports Club Murder Case."
جريمة قتل نادي الرياضة
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Cap.
قبّعة
Next episode features a popular sports club.
تقع أحداث الحلقة القادمة !في نادي رياضات شعبيّ
Come on, Genta. Let's do it again.
!هيّا يا غينتا، سنركض جولةً أخرى
I can't keep running...
...لم أعد أستطيع